## GOLDI TEWARI

+1(551)297-9255 \$\dightarrow\$ goldi.tewari9@gmail.com \$\display\$ Hillsboro, OR https://www.linkedin.com/in/goldi-tewari-1257711a/

### **SUMMARY**

I transform numbers into stories. My three-year Data Science journey has taken me from nimble startups to Fortune 100 giants like Nike and Humana in retail and Healthcare sector. With a PhD and a Master's in the quantitative field, I excel in **SQL** and **Python**, create magic with **Power BI** and **Tableau**, and am certified in trailblazing platforms like **Databricks** and **IBM cloud**.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Business Analytics, University of Louisville, Kentucky, USA PhD in Communication Science (Quantitative focus), Ghent University, Belgium

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming** SQL, Python, R, SPSS

Data Visualization
 Power BI, Tableau, Amazon QuickSight
 Platforms
 Databricks, Github, AWS, Snowflake, Azure

Certifications Databricks (Lakehouse Fundamental), SAS, IBM Cloud, EDITED (retail intelligence)
Statistics Predictive analytics, Regression, Forecasting, A/B Testing, Mixed-effects Models

AI skills Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing (NLP), Generative AI

### **EXPERIENCE**

# 1 Data Scientist - Consumer Insights (contract)

Nov 2023 - April 2024 Beaverton, OR

### Nike, Inc.

- Led Market and Competitor analytics project from start to finish. Collaborated, explored data, **ETL** developed **Python, SQL scripts**.
- Build Tableau dashboards on retail and supply chain metrics like revenue, Average Unit Retail (AUR), Market share, Market size, Net sales, Average Selling Price. These dashboards helped the company to strategically plan its market competitiveness throughout a product lifecycle.
- Gathered data and applied **tokenization methods for NLP project**. It led to streamlined text data preprocessing and enhanced model performance and personalized merchandise recommendation
- Identified target consumer segments and top 10 product substitutes in US and South Korean markets for an upcoming **product launch** using a **conjoint analysis** simulator.
- Gathered data requirements, build metrics on Consumer Product Preference. Reported on **personalized merchandise recommendation**.
- Worked within the leadership team to gather, analyze, and interpret retail data from various sources including point of sale, transaction data, and consumer surveys, reviews, Nike website.
- Utilized statistical techniques (hypothesis testing, linear regression, and multiple regression) to extract insights and drive informed decision-making.
- Tools used: MS SQL Server, Python(NLTK, Scikit-learn, NumPy, Pandas), Databricks, Snowflake, Tableau, Github, Edited (a retail intelligence tool).

# 2 Data Scientist - Pharmacy Marketing Analytics (contract)

May 2022 - Nov 2023 Louisville, KY

## Humana, Inc.

- Developed and **automated** advanced **Power BI** dashboards reducing data processing and reporting time by 70 percent.
- Built a Marketing Mix Model (MMM) using Multiple Linear Regression (MLR) to predict total drug sales through various pharmacy marketing campaigns. I used various multiple marketing features (e.g. type of marketing channels (email, call, sms, print, landing page traffic); total number of outbound calls, frequency of calls; landing page traffic (total sessions, total visits, log ins), total number of drug refills, physician engagement etc.) to predict sales.
- Built a model predicting COVID-19 vaccine hesitancy among Humana members. The model was ranked among the top 50 in a case competition in the US. Regression techniques e.g. random forest, logistic regression and Machine Learning (ML) techniques such as **XGBoost** were used in building this model.
- Clustered Humana members to discover hidden patterns in their characteristics & used unsupervised clustering algorithms like K-means for clustering.
- Led Marketing Analytics and reporting initiatives of all Pharmacy Benefit Management (PBM) campaigns with actionable data and insights across the full customer campaign lifecycle.
- Used Marketing analytics and advanced methodologies including customer lifetime value, media mix modeling, multi-touch attribution, time-series forecasting, Bayesian analysis, panel data methods, regression techniques, selection models, hazard modeling, structural equation modeling, and latent class regression.
- Conducted **A/B** and multivariate tests on email, SMS, Direct mail, landing pages traffic leading to an improvement of conversion rates by 20 percent.
- Tools used: Oracle SQL, Power BI, Python, Azure DevOps

# 3 Business Analyst

Sept 2021 - May 2022

### Workrede (a mobile employee engagement cloud platform)

Louisville, KY

- Produced sales and buyer analytics summaries utilizing **Amazon QuickSight** dashboards for the leadership team.
- SQL queries, ETL, A/B Testing, and statistical analysis (e.g. hypothesis testing, experimentation, regressions) with statistical packages in R & Python.
- Tools used: SQL, Amazon Quicksights, Python, Zira, Tableplus, Metabase

# 4 Program Manager

Nov 2018 - Nov 2019 Hyderabad, India

### National Institute of Agricultural Extension Management (MANAGE)

- Lead the US Agency for International Development (USAID)-India Collaborative Program (Feed The Future India Triangular Training (FTF ITT) Program) in India.
- Global role, with accountability to stakeholders across Indian government, 20 nations and USAID. I was responsible for managing 40 international agricultural trainings as per the US and Indian government's standards.
- Executed trainee's professional data synchronization to create and maintain seamless training experience.
- Collected and analyze data on training effectiveness for 1000 professional from 20 different countries.
- Troubleshot discrepancies in trainee profile information using a combination of defined processes and research.

#### PROJECTS

Dashboard bulding Build Power BI and Tableau dashboard on various retail and healthcare metrics

**Predictive Modeling.** Developed a model predicting COVID-19 vaccine hesitancy among Humana members, ranked among the top 50 nationwide.

**Experimental Research.** Conducted 3 experimental research projects across US, Belgian and Indian consumers. Modeled and published results on how companies should frame messages during a crisis.

### LEADERSHIP/PRESENTATIONS

- Team Leader-Humana-Mays Healthcare Analytics Case Competition 2021.
- Finalist speaker-TedX Ghent PhD Contest 2017 video
- Presenter-The European Marketing Academy Conference (EMAC), 2016, Oslo, Norway.
- Presenter-The Etmaal van de Communicatiewetenschap (ETMAAL) Feb 4-5, 2016, Amsterdam.

### **AWARDS**

- International Erasmus Mundus Scholarship-European Commission 2014
- International Student and Scholar Award, University of Louisville, Louisville, KY. news

### REFERENCES

- Maria Frushicheva, Lead Data Scientist, Nike (My manager at Nike)
- Michael Ziegler, Director D and A Insights Nike (my project manager at Nike)
- Demet Metan, Cofounder and Head of Data Science and Analytics, Full Spectrum Insights (was previously working with Humana and was my manager)